Charles M. Kurtz
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1843-1940, undated, Series 2:
  - Correspondence, March 1-31, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 1-28)
    (Emery H. Barton, Geo. Corlisa, Frank Gaiennie, Halsey C. Ives, J.H. Gest-Cincinnti Museum Association, Harrison S. Morris, A.T. Goshorn-Cincinnati Museum Association, W.M.R. French, A.H. Griffith, Ogden Wood)
  - Correspondence, April 1-30, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 29-54)
    (Chicago Evening Post, E.W. Heysinger, Patty Thum, A.H. Griffith, B.W. Woodward, James W. Alexander, John R. Tait, Charles M. Kurtz, Otto H. Bacher, Charles Sprague Pearce, Halsey C. Ives, Colin Campbell Cooper, L.A. Coonley Ward)
  - Correspondence, May 1-15, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 55-77)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Starkweather family, Frank W. Benson, Carle J. Blumner, J.H. Dolph, Mrs. C.B. Coman, Wm. Morgan, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, May 16-31, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 78-99)
    (Jules Guérin, Frederick B. Williams, Halsey C. Ives, H.O. Walker, Samuel P. Avery, Mrs. L.A. Coonley Ward, Paul Charlton-Chair, Trans-Mississippi and International Exposition, J. Alden Weir, Zachary T. Lindsey-Trans-Mississippi and International Exposition, Chas. W. Eaton)
  - Correspondence, June 1-15, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 100-131)
    (Will H. Low, Wm. H. Howe, Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, J. H. Gest, E. Frischhof)
  - Correspondence, June 16-30, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 132-176)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, Cecilia Beaux, Harrison S. Morris, Henry Farrer, Wm. H. Howe)
  - Correspondence, July 1-15, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 177-214)
    (J.H. Gest, Julia S. Kurtz, Charles S. Kurtz, A.T. Bricher, Mrs. Bertha Lea Low, Robert W. Vonnoh)
  - Correspondence, July 16-31, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 215-256)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, J.B. Bristol, Charles Grafly, Harrison S. Morris, Stephenson family)
  - Correspondence, August 1-10, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 257-297)
    (Henry C. Lee, Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, Stu. Laurence, Francis Wheaton, Roswell S. Hill, Henry C. Lee, Starkweather family, W. W. Thum)
  - Correspondence, August 11-15, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 298-330)
    (E. A. Anderson-Louisville Art League, E.L. Henry, Edmund C. Tarbell, Stephenson family, M. Knoedler & Co., Charles M. Kurtz, F.W. Stokes, Fred. W. ?, St. Louis Exposition and Music Hall Association, Henry Mosley)
  - Correspondence, August 16-31, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 331-362)
    (Edmund Tarbell, J.H. Gest-Cincinnati Museum Association, Charles Ward Rhodes, H. Siddons Mowbray, Patty Thum, Mrs. L. A. Coonley Ward, Sam. P. Avery, Charles Melville Dewey, Edmonia A. Anderson-Louisville Art League, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, September 1-10, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 363-392)
    (Sam. P. Avery, C.B. Woodward Printing Co., Patty Thum, "Steve" Horatio S. Stevenson, Julia S. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, Halsey C. Ives, L.H.Meakin-Society of Western Artists)
  - Correspondence, September 11-30, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 393-426)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Alexander Reid, Will H. Low, Cornelia F. Maury, Henry R. Poore, A.H. Griffith, Isabel Macdougall-The Chicago Evening Post, Harrison S. Morris, Orrin S. Parsons, Charles Francis Browne-Brush and Pencil, Geo. F. Brownell, James D. Spriggs, Theo. Cooley, James Paterson)
  - Correspondence, October 1-31, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 427-452)
    (Sam. P. Avery, Wm. Verplanck Birney, B. W. Woodward, F. S. Church, Alex. Reid, Irving R. Wiles, Sam. P. Avery, Chas. B. McCormack, Charles M. Kurtz, Chas. Sedelmeyer, James D. Springgs, Geo. F. Brownell)
  - Correspondence, November 1-20, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 453-479)
    (American Water Color Society, Patty Thum, The Lotos Club, Charles Sedelmeyer, Sam. P. Avery, Walter C. Hartson, J. Francis Murphy, Wm. H. Howe, F. S. Church, J. C. Sherlock, E. Fischhof, "Steve"-brother of R. Macauley Stevenson, James D. Spriggs)
  - Correspondence, November 21-30, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 480-505)
    (Harrison S. Morris, Alex. Reid, Sam. P. Avery, James D. Spriggs, Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Ward Rhodes, Robert Walker-Royal Glasgow Institute of the Fine Arts, F.W.Gookin, A.H Griffith)
  - Correspondence, December 1-10, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 506-524)
    (Sam. P. Avery, Sara Hallowell, Nina G. Batchelor, Chas. H. Wyman & Co-Custom House Brokers, A.H. Griffith, Ellis Wainwright, Marcus Benjamin-U.S. National Museum)
  - Correspondence, December 11-31, 1898 (Reel 4816, Frame 525-543)
    (Geo. F. Brownell, Marcus Benjamin, J.H. Gest, Halsey C. Ives, Charles M. Kurtz, A.H. Griffith?-Detroit Museum of Art)
  - Correspondence, Correspondence, 1899? (Reel 4816, Frame 544-557)
    (Geo. K. Andrews, Charles M. Kurtz, John B. Cauldwell)
  - Correspondence, January 1-10, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 558-571)
    (Geo. A. McKinstry, Marcus Benjamin, R. Swain Gifford, Halsey C. Ives, T. Addison Richards)
  - Correspondence, January 11-31, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 572-588)
    (Emil Loir, A.H. Griffith, Elizabeth Menefee, Halsey C. Ives, American Art Association-J. Ortgres, J. C. Sherlock, John B. Cauldwell)
  - Correspondence, February 1-15, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 589-604)
    (Reid Northrop, Halsey C. Ives, Harrison S. Morris, J. H. Gest, Sam. P. Avery, William T. Evans)
  - Correspondence, February 16-28, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 605-635)
    (R. Swain Gifford, Dudley Smith-Greater America Exposition, Omaha, John B. Cauldwell, Charles Ward Rhodes, J.C. Sherlock, Lyman H. Weeks, General Manager, St. Louis Exposition and Musical Hall Association)
  - Correspondence, March 1-5, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 636-659)
    (John B. Cauldwell-United States Commission to the Paris Exposition of 1900, Marcus Benjamin, Letitia B. Hart, Cornelia Fellaway, Charles H. Pepper)
  - Correspondence, March 6-20, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 660-686)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Frank Gaiennie, John B. Cauldwell, B.W. Woodward, William Bailey Faxon, Ikey-Charles Ward Rhodes)
  - Correspondence, March 21-31, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 687-713)
    (J.H. Gest-Cincinnati Museum Association, John B. Cauldwell, H.K. Bush-Brown-Architectural League of New York, Alexander Reid, Charles M. Kurtz, Wm. Victor Wallace, Julia S. Kurtz, Ferdinand W. Peck)
  - Correspondence, April 1-15, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 714-743)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, A.L. Bridgeman-Secretary, Peary Arctic Club, Mary Bacon Ford, Ikey-Charles Ward Rhodes, Marcus Benjamin)
  - Correspondence, April 16-30, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 744-760)
    (A.T. Bricher, Jules Guérin, Will H. Low, B.W. Woodward, Theo. Cooley, F. Hopkinson Smith, Clark Sampson-St. Louis Exposition and Music Hall Association, Fred. W. Kost, Will S. Robinson, Thomas W. Wood, Harrison S. Morris)
  - Correspondence, May 1-8, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 761-785)
    (Enid Yandell, Maria Brooks, J.C. Nicoll, Charles Ward Rhodes?, W. Elmer Schofield, R. Swain Gifford, P.A. Gross, Louis Paul Dessar, Georgia W. Fraser-art editor of Art Education, Charles Ward Rhodes)
  - Correspondence, May 11-20, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 786-806)
    (Cornelia Fellaway, B.D. Woodward, John B. Cauldwell, Mary Graton Bartlett, Geo. Barrie, Geo. H. Smillie, Maria Brooks, Walter Shirlaw)
  - Correspondence, May 21-31, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 807-818)
    (John B. Cauldwell, Halsey C. Ives)
  - Correspondence, June 1-30, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 819-851)
    (Charles Ward Rhodes, John B. Cauldwell, Chas. P. Gruppe, Charles Sprague Pearce, Charles M. Kurtz, Tocky-Starkweather)
  - Correspondence, July 1-31, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 852-692)
    (Kurtz family, Starkweather family, Fritz Thaulow, Georgia Gross, Charles M. Kurtz, Frederick Dielman, John B. Cauldwell, Stephenson family, Geo. Barrie, Charles Ward Rhodes, Geo. H. Story, P.A. Gross)
  - Correspondence, August 1-31, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 693-907)
    (Frank Russell Green, Sybil Rinehart, Geo. F. Brownell, Ikey- Charles Ward Rhodes, J. H. Gest, John H. McGibbons-United States Commission, Sam. P. Avery)
  - Correspondence, September 1-30, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 908-934)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Frank Gaiennie, Charles Ward Rhodes, Marcus Benjamin, J.H. Fry, B.W. Woodward, John B. Cauldwell, Halsey C. Ives, Frederick W. Gardner)
  - Correspondence, October 1-31, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 935-955)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Ward Rhodes, Edmund H. Murphy, Halsey C. Ives, Marcus Benjamin)
  - Correspondence, November 1-30, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 956-987)
    (Harrison S. Morris, Charles M. Kurtz, Cornelia F. Maury, Charles M. Dewey, C. de Vivo for Eugene Fischhof)
  - Correspondence, December 1-31, 1899 (Reel 4816, Frame 988-1028)
    (Charles Ward Rhodes, Steve Stevenson?, Frederick E. Bartlett, Kurtz family, Charles M. Kurtz, Starkweather family, Lyman H. Weeks, B.W. Woodward)
  - Correspondence, January 1-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1029-1081)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, C. de Vivo, Reid Northrop, Halsey C. Ives, Charles Ward Rhodes, and Julia S. Kurtz undated letters, probably from early summer of 1899)
  - Correspondence, February 1-28, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1082-1113)
    (Harrison S. Morris, L.A.C. Ward, F. A. Bridgeman, R. Swain Gifford, James Grant, Halsey C. Ives, Marcus Benjamin, Charles Ward Rhodes, J. H. Gest, L.A.C. Ward, William Victor Wallace)
  - Correspondence, March 1-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1114-1133)
    (Mary Davis Chambers, H.K. Bush-Brown, Geo. H. Story, W.M.R. French-Art Institute of Chicago, J.H. Dolph, Alfred Fischhof, J.J. Albright)
  - Correspondence, April 1-10, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1134-1147)
    (Lyman H. Weeks, Halsey C. Ives, T. C. Noé-firm of S. P. Avery)
  - Correspondence, April 11-30, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1148-1158)
    (W.V. Birney, Charles Ward Rhodes, Harrison S. Morris, C. de Vivo for firm of Eugene Fischhof)
  - Correspondence, May 1-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1159-1185)
    (Ikey-Charles Ward Rhodes, Morton M. Casseday, J. B. Bristol, John. B. Cauldwell, Stephenson family, Henry S. Hubbell)
  - Correspondence, June 10-20, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1186-1197)
    (Horace Porter-United States Ambassador to France, H.O. Tanner, Harrison S. Morris, Marcus Benjamin, A. Bartholemy, Richard Lloyd Jones)
  - Correspondence, June 21-30, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1198-1228)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Richard Lloyd Jones, B.W. Woodward, Kurtz family, St. Louis Exposition and Music Hall Association, Geo. W. Ochs-The New York Times, John D. Cauldwell)
  - Correspondence, July 1-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1229-1235)
    (John B. Cauldwell, Geo. Barrie, Morton Casseday)
  - Correspondence, August 1-30, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1236-1260)
    (Richard Lloyd Jones, B. Barthélemy, Louis Paul Dessar, Henry S. Hubbell, Geo. W. Ochs, E.R. Bacon, F. Curley, Starkweather family, Charles Ward Rhodes, Theodore C. Noé)
  - Correspondence, September 1-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1261-1285)
    (Julia S. Kurtz, Kurtz family, B.W. Woodward, Charles Ward Rhodes, Rodman Wanamaker, A. Barthélemy, Cornelia F. Maury)
  - Correspondence, October 1-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1286-1308)
    (Starkweather family, Marcus Benjamin, New York Water Color Club, Noyes, Platt and Co., Cornelia B. Sage-Buffalo Fine Arts Academy-letter dated 1914, Louis Frohlish for Eugéne Fischhoff, T.C. Noé for Sam. P. Avery, Hensel, Bruckmann & Lorbacher Custom House Brokers, Chester Woodward)
  - Correspondence, November 1-20, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1309-1338)
    (Halsey C. Ives, St. Nicholas magazine, thank you notes for photographs from ship board companions)
  - Correspondence, November 21-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1339-1352)
    (notes from ship board companions, Augustus Franzein, H.K. Bush-Brown, R.J. Haight-publisher of The Monumental News, Mrs. Lydia? Coonley Ward)
  - Correspondence, December 1-15, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1353-1370)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Anne Abbott Brownell, The Monumental News, George H. Bogart, Frederick E. Bartlett, Charles Ward Rhodes)
  - Correspondence, December 16-31, 1900 (Reel 4816, Frame 1371-1384)
    (Victor D. Brenner, The Monumental News, Frederick E. Bartlett, Grace Isabel Colbron)
  - Letters, 1901, undated (Reel 4817, Frame 1-6)
    (Roger Riordan-Pan-American Exposition 1901, copy of preliminary announcement of artists participating in the Pan-American Exposition, Halsey C. Ives)
  - Correspondence, January 1-31, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 7-39)
    (F.C. Howe, Halsey C. Ives, Emery H. Barton, Charles M. Kurtz, Alfred V. Churchill, Steve-Horatio S. Stevenson, Ogden Wood, Frederick E. Bartlett)
  - Correspondence, February 1-28, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 40-73)
    (The Monumental News, A. Fischhof, Halsey C. Ives, Arthur Stedman, Kurtz family, Victor D. Brenner, Henry Wolf, Halsey C. Ives)
  - Correspondence, March 1-31, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 74-97)
    (J.B. Botto, Starkweather family, Halsey C. Ives, Charles Ward Rhodes, Frederick E. Bartlett, Geo. McKinstry)
  - Correspondence, April 1-15, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 98-122)
    (W.M.R. French, Charles Parsons, Emery Pottle for The Criterion, Wm. H. Coffin for Pan-American Exposition, Charles M. Kurtz, Ogden Wood, Frederic C. Howe, K. Takahashi)
  - Correspondence, April 16-30, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 123-149)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Geo. K. Andrews, Frederick E. Bartlett, Ogden Wood, The Criterion)
  - Correspondence, May 1-15, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 150-167)
    (Burton Thompson for Missouri Society, Wm. A. Coffin, Emery Pottle, Charles Ward Rhodes, Ikey-Charles Ward Rhodes, Marcus Benjamin)
  - Correspondence, May 16-31, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 168-181)
    (John J. Emery, J.N. Marble, Reid Northrop)
  - Correspondence, June 1-15, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 182-199)
    (Doubleday, Page & Co., Pan-American Exposition Press Dept., Richard Lloyd Jones, Reid Northrop, Charles Parsons, Halsey C. Ives)
  - Correspondence, June 16-30, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 200-219)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Ward Rhodes, Ogden Wood, Doubleday, Page & Co.)
  - Correspondence, July 1-30, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 220-257)
    (Charles Ward Rhodes, Cornelia F. Maury, J.P.H. Cunningham, Charles M. Kurtz, Halsey C. Ives, J.G. Brown, Isabella Starkweather, J.E. Elwell)
  - Correspondence, August 1-15, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 258-291)
    (Doubleday, Page & Co., Charles M. Kurtz, Halsey C. Ives, Charles Ward Rhodes, Ogden Wood)
  - Correspondence, August 16-31, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 292-325)
    (Charles Ward Rhodes, Harper & Bros, Marcus Benjamin, Doubleday, Page & Co., Halsey C. Ives, F.C. DeLeon, John LaFarge, J.G. Brown)
  - Correspondence, September 1-10, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 326-344)
    (J.E. Elwell, Kurtz family, J.B. Botto, Julia S. Kurtz, Geo. F. Brownell)
  - Correspondence, September 11-30, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 345-367)
    (Morton M. Casseday, Charles de Kay for The National Arts Club, Victor J.Brenner, Tock-C.C. Starkweather, Ikey A. Barthèlemy, Wm. Victor Wallace, Cornelia F. Maury)
  - Correspondence, October 1-15, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 368-392)
    (Philip R. Sawyer, J.H. Gest, Harrison S. Morris, Roger Riordan, Emery H. Barton, F.E.A. Curley)
  - Correspondence, October 16-31, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 393-413)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Henry Romeike, Harrison S. Morris, Julia S. Kurtz, Geo. F. Brownell)
  - Correspondence, November 1-30, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 414-443)
    (Mrs. Morton M. Casseday, Philip R. Sawyer, Constantino de Vivo, Charles M. Kurtz, S.P. Annan, Harrison S. Morris, Ikey-Constantino de Vivo)
  - Correspondence, December 1-10, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 444-469)
    (Tock-C.C. Starkweather, Charles M. Kurtz, Ikey-Constantino de Vivo, A. Barthélemy, Ogden Wood)
  - Correspondence, December 11-25, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 470-493)
    (B.B. Vallentine, J. H. Dolph, Marcus Benjamin, ? Cuiley, Ikey-Constantino de Vivo, Eugène Fischhof, W.L. Sheldon)
  - Correspondence, December 26-31, 1901 (Reel 4817, Frame 494-515)
    (Clara McChesney, Curator of Paintings, St. Louis Museum- Charles Ward Rhodes, Charles M. Kurtz, Frederick W. Gookin, Eugène Fischhof, Constantino de Vivo, William Victor Wallace)
  - Correspondence, 1901? (Reel 4817, Frame 516-524)
    (L. P. di Cesnola, Edith H. Ogden)
  - Correspondence, January 1-15, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 525-550)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Ward Rhodes, J.B. Botto, C. Brunner for Chas. Sedelmeyer, Geo. F. Brownell, Frederick E. Bartlett, Geo. McKinstry, W.B. Stevens-St. Louis World's Fair)
  - Correspondence, January 16-22, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 551-570)
    (J. Whitelaw Hamilton, Reid Northrop, Kurtz family, Charles Ward Rhodes, F. Miranda, A Barthélemy, American Art Association, Geo. F. Brownell, Julia S. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, January 23-31, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 571-596)
    (Starkweather family, Reid Northrop, F. Edwin Elwell for Metropolitan Museum of Art, Halsey C. Ives, Charles Ward Rhodes, Laura Sedgwick Collins, Julia S. Kurtz, John La Farge, Theo. Hausen-Consulate of Sweden and Norway, Wilfred H. Schoff for Philadelphia Comercial Museum)
  - Correspondence, February 1-15, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 597-620)
    (Morton M. Casseday, A. Barthélemy, Julia S. Kurtz, René Ferry for Minerva, Frederick E. Bartlett, Alexander Roche, Morton M. Casseday, Halsey C. Ives, Theodore C. Noé for Sam. P. Avery)
  - Correspondence, February 16-28, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 621-655)
    (Theodore C. Noé, Frederick Dielman, Julia S. Kurtz, Geo. McKinstry, Mercantile Library of St. Louis, Charles Ward Rhodes, Theodore C. Noé, Frederick E. Bartlett)
  - Correspondence, March 1-15, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 656-678)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, James Paterson, Philip B. Sawyer, Carnegie Institute)
  - Correspondence, March 16-31, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 679-693)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Henry S. Hubbell, A. Barthélemy, H. S. Morris, Reil Northrop)
  - Correspondence, April 1-30, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 694-717)
    (Halsey C. Ives, Ikey-Charles Ward Rhodes, W.S. Chaplin-Washington University, Julia S. Kurtz, Starkweather family, Nina Starkweather?, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, May 1-31, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 718-737)
    (Holmes Smith-Society of Western Artists, A. Barthélemy, Ogden Wood, J. William Fosdick-National Society of Mural Painters, Charles Boulet de Mondel, Victor Brenner, James Paterson)
  - Correspondence, June 1-30, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 738-761)
    (Theodore C. Noé Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, C. T. Brainard & Co., St. Louis Club)
  - Correspondence, July 1-15, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 762-777)
    (St. Louis Club, A. Barthélemy, Geo. N. Andre, Edwin H. Wuerpel)
  - Correspondence, July 16-25, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 778-801)
    (Theodore C. Noé, R. Macaulay Stevenson, C. Brunner, Charles M. Kurtz, A. Barthélemy, Grosvenor Thomas, J. B. Bennett & Sons, Picture Dealers, Chas. H. Ault)
  - Correspondence, July 26-31, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 802-827)
    (Alexander Reid, George F. Parker-U.K. Representative to the Universal Exposition, St. Louis, 1904, J. WHitelaw Hamilton, Starkweather family, T. Corsan Morton, James Paterson, George Pirie, Harry Spence, Chas. S. Hamblin-Art Dept., St. Louis World's Fair)
  - Correspondence, August 1-31, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 828-861)
    (Charles de Kay for The Venice Campanile Fund, Theodore C. Noé, J. M. Crawford, Edwin H. Wuerpel, David Gauld, Washington & Jefferson College, F.E.A. Curley, Alexander Reid, Marvin Eddy, C. de Vivo, Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Ward Rhodes, William Kennedy)
  - Correspondence, September 1-30, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 862-868)
    (? Curley)
  - Correspondence, October 1-31, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 869-888)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, W. Victor Wallace, Stephenson family, Marcus Benjamin, Halsey C. Ives)
  - Correspondence, November 1-10, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 889-913)
    (Municipal Art Society, C.J. Zolnay, John Getz, Harper's Weekly, Geo. F. Brownell, Charles Nagel, F.O. Sylvester, Michel de Carnowsky, Holmes Smith-Society of Western Artists)
  - Correspondence, November 11-20, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 914-950)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Charles Ward Rhodes, Halsey C. Ives, William Victor Wallace, Durand-Ruel, New York Galleries, Henry Romeike Press Cutting Bureau, Wilson Eyre)
  - Correspondence, November 21-25, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 951-970)
    (F.O. Sylvester, Wilson Eyre, Charles M. Kurtz, C.S. Hamblin-St. Louis World's Fair, William Victor Wallace, W.S. Budworth & Son, Packers and Shippers, Robert? Bringhurst, Michel de Carnowsky)
  - Correspondence, November 26-30, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 971-986)
    (Starkweather family, Charles M. Kurtz, Ernst Kegel)
  - Correspondence, December 1-31, 1902 (Reel 4817, Frame 987-1001)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Japan Society, Chas. H. Ault, Isaac S. Taylor-St. Louis World's Fair, Michel de Carnowsky, George F. Kunz, and Alexander Reid letter dated 1901)
  - Correspondence: Charles M. Kurtz, incomplete,, 1903? (Reel 4817, Frame 1002-1010)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Edwin H. Wuerpel)
  - Correspondence:, January 1-5, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1011-1026)
    (Emery H. Barton, Enid Yandell, Edw. H. Semple, Charles M. Kurtz, Starkweather family, Laura Sedgwick Collins, C.S. Hamblin)
  - Correspondence, January 6-10, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1027-1038)
    (Laura Sedgwick Collins, C.S. Hamblin, Camera Club of New York, Charles M. Kurtz)
  - Correspondence, January 11-31, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1039-1064)
    (John Getz, Charles M. Kurtz, Harrison S. Morris, A. Barthélemy, Geo. H. Story)
  - Correspondence, February 1-20, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1065-1079)
    (Starkweather family, W.M.R. French-Art Institute of Chicago, Eugene Fischhof, D.C. Ball, Stephenson family, Kurtz family, Emery Pottle for The Criterion)
  - Correspondence, February 21-28, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1080-1094)
    (W.M.R. French, Charles M. Kurtz, Marvin Eddy, Jules R. Mersfelder, L.A. Coonley Ward, Ogden Wood?)
  - Correspondence, March 1-31, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1095-1115)
    (Frederick J.V. Skiff-St. Louis World's Fair, J.H. Kingwill, Merry delle Hoyt, Charles de Kay, Missouri Society, Zorlah M. Burroughs, Starkweather family, Strobridge Lithography Co, Paul Jones, F.S. Lamb, Harrison S. Morris)
  - Correspondence, April 1-10, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1116-1135)
    (Maria Brooks, J. H. Kingwill, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, Halsey C. Ives, C.S. Hamblin)
  - Correspondence, April 11-20, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1136-1157)
    (E.E. Seavy, Thomas Allen, Gari Melchers, Julia S. Kurtz, C.S. Hamblin, Strobridge Lithography Co., Chas. H. Ault, Alexander Roche, Gottschalk Printing Co., Starkweather family)
  - Correspondence, April 21-30, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1158-1170)
    (Emery Pottle for The Criterion, Julia S. Kurtz, Florence N. Levy for the American Art Annual, Dr. Skiff, Emery Pottle, Rhode C. Chase, Emery H. Barton)
  - Correspondence, May 1-30, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1171-1195)
    (Charles M. Kurtz, Stephenson family, F. Edwin Elwell, W.A. Brearley, Halsey C. Ives, George J. Zolnay, Morton M. Casseday, M. Knoedler & Co.)
  - Correspondence, June 1-30, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1196-1237)
    (St. Louis School of Fine Arts, Morton Casseday, Tock-Starkweather, Charles M. Kurtz, E.H. Wuerpel, Henry Wolf, James D. Smillie, Frederick Deilman, Washington and Jefferson College The Pandora, J.B. Botto)
  - Correspondence, July 1-31, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1238-1258)
    (C.E. Hutchings, Cornelia F. Maury, D.C. Ball, Stephenson family, Frank V.? Dudley, Tock-Starkweather)
  - Correspondence, August 1-31, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1259-1279)
    (Edna Fischel, Metropolitan Museum of Art, W. M. R. French, Stephenson family, Marcus Benjamin)
  - Correspondence, September 1-30, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1280-1293)
    (William A. Coffin, E.H. Wuerpel, Marcus Benjamin, Frank V.? Dudley, J.B. Botto, A. Shugio on behalf of Y. Otsuka, Rodman Wanamaker)
  - Correspondence, October-December, 1903 (Reel 4817, Frame 1294-1318)
    (Morton Casseday, Starkweather family, C.S. Hamblin, D.B.K.- Davis B. Kurtz, Charles M. Kurtz, Julia S. Kurtz, Collier's Weekly, George F. Brownell, F.O. Sylvester-Society of Western Artists)
  - Letters, 1904, undated (Reel 4817, Frame 1319-1337)